

# Alejandro Santiago

I.T. Specialist



# **Professional Summary**

Highly skilled I.T. Specialist with a broad base of experience in technical support, operations, administration, and development. Extremely skilled at focused and creative problem resolution, delivering high levels of customer and client satisfaction, collaborating with internal and external entities, and an uncanny ability to consistently respond favorably to a wide range of technical challenges.



# **Work History**

2019-07 -Current

## Information Technology Specialist

TCC Software Solutions, Indianapolis, IN

- Increased overall company technology productivity by 25%.
- Worked with software development team on reported errors and bugs on newly released software and assisted in deployment of release fixes.
- Worked closely with management teams to plan, develop, coordinate and execute technical strategies aligned to client's vision, mission and purpose.

2018-10 -2019-07

## I.T. Application Administrator

Hirschbach Motor Lines Inc., Dubuque, IA

- Implemented new applications, features and enhancements to existing applications in order to keep company operations above 99%.
- Managed, Maintained and Administration CISCO Unified Communications Systems to include Call



#### **Address**

Anchorage, AK, 99503

#### Phone

(907) 782-9185

#### E-mail

developer@alejandrosantia go.dev

#### **WWW**

https://alejandrosantiago.de v

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alejandro-santiago-dev



**End-user support** 



Network administration



Problem-solving skills



Device configuration



Confidential data management



Hardware installations



Software updates



Advanced computer proficiency



Customer service expert



- Manager, Unity Connection, UCCX Administration, and VistaPoint integrated platform.
- Maintained and monitored Barracuda Spam
   Firewall, Outlook Exchange Admin, vSphere Web
   Client and VMHorizon 7 Administration, Spiceworks
   Ticketing and ScreenConnect implementations,
   and VEEAM backup applications.

## 2017-12 -2018-10

## Information Technology Specialist

Hirschbach Motor Lines Inc., Dubuque, IA

- Resolved escalated issues by serving as subject matter expert on wide-ranging issues. Reduced number of longstanding issues by 90%.
- Facilitated best user experience through continuous support, training classes, webinars, improvements and communication of system changes.
- Performed daily system monitoring, verifying integrity and availability of hardware, server resources, systems and key processes.



# **Education**

1999-08 -2001-07

# **High School Diploma**

Pine Forest High School - Fayetteville, NC



## Certifications

2021-10

PCEP - Certified Entry-Level Python Programmer, October 2021



PCEP - Python Programming Language



C Programming Language



Average

HTML, CSS, JavaScript



OOP - Object Oriented

Programming



Very Good

CISCO CM (CAll Manager)



Java Programming Language

